Tell us about a time when you were learning something new and
Beri tahu kami saat Anda belajar hal baru dan
you had to struggle.
harus berjuang.
&gt;&gt; Okay, Katherine, if you're going to ask our students to share
Baik, Katherine, jika Anda meminta siswa kita berbagi
their vulnerable stories on the Internet.
kisah krisis mereka di Internet.
&gt;&gt; Yeah. &gt;&gt; We have to lead by example.
- Lalu? - Kita harus memberi contoh.
&gt;&gt; Okay, fair enough.
Baiklah, cukup adil.
You go first.
Anda duluan.
&gt;&gt; Okay. [LAUGH] Well I've been
Baiklah.
learning to play the piano for about eight months.
Yah, saya belajar bermain piano selama 8 bulan.
&gt;&gt; Oh okay.
Oh, oke.
&gt;&gt; And the toughest bits for me have been getting one hand right and
Hal tersulit bagi saya adalah menjaga salah satu tangan benar,
then getting the right hand right and then putting those two things together.
lalu menjaga tangan kanan benar sebelum memadukan keduanya.
But, when it comes out just so beautiful its like [SOUND].
Tapi, hasilnya terdengar sangat indah seperti... (meniru bunyi).
&gt;&gt; Oh, that sounds really good.
Oh, itu terdengar sangat bagus.
&gt;&gt; I've been playing with my friends, it's really fun.
Saya bermain untuk teman. Itu sangat menyenangkan.
&gt;&gt; Wait, you haven't played for me.
Tunggu, Anda belum bermain untuk saya.
&gt;&gt; Well, we'll see if we stay friends till the end of this course
Kita lihat saja apa kita masih berteman sampai akhir kursus ini.
&gt;&gt; Okay, then.
Baiklah, kalau begitu.
&gt;&gt; Your turn.
Giliran Anda.
&gt;&gt; I've struggled with learning Chinese my whole life.
Baik. Saya berjuang belajar Bahasa Cina sepanjang hidup saya.
&gt;&gt; Wait, you speak Chinese?
Tunggu, Anda berbicara Bahasa Cina?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
Iya.
[FOREIGN] &gt;&gt; Wow.
- (menyapa dalam Bahasa Cina) - Wow!
&gt;&gt; It's no big deal.
Ini bukan perkara besar.
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; So, I think the hardest part of
Menurut saya bagian tersulit dari
learning Chinese has been trying to learn all the vocab words and
belajar Bahasa Cina adalah mempelajari semua kosakata,
trying to put them together in complete sentences without tripping up.
berusaha memadukannya dalam kalimat lengkap tanpa tertukar.
&gt;&gt; You know this story of yours is reminding me that
Anda tahu, kisah Anda ini mengingatkan saya bahwa
learning how to make an Android app is like learning a new language.
belajar membuat aplikasi Android seperti belajar bahasa baru.
Okay, I could see that.
Oke, saya bisa memahami itu.
&gt;&gt; Okay, well those are our stories.
Baik, itulah kisah kita.
Now I want our students to share their vulnerable stories.
Sekarang saya ingin siswa kita membagi kisah krisis mereka.
Tell us about a time when you learned something new and it was a struggle.
Beri tahu kami saat belajar hal baru dan itu adalah perjuangan.